Postcards
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Postcards, 2.1.7
  - Miscellaneous postcards, undated; 6 (Box 1603)
    - Verso: Our Christian Era. Christianity is the invinceable bulwark against fear, hatred, avarice, politics, purpose, cruelty in peace, selfishness, misunderstanding. Line after line of marchers, down, down, our Christian calendar; panoplied youth in armor, here and there a sword hilt graved by a heart that loved beauty, beauty used for the kill, chasulbles of broidered gold with jewels, candelabra of gold, candles for prayers and everywhere the symbol of the Cross. Armies of thousands upon thousands, marching, marching, marching. Drums, bugles and more drums. Yes! And flags, flags everywhere. Shining bayonets guilded by the sunset. Prayers for victory in the murderous battlefield and bombing the houses of God. Bodies frozen in moats of the dark ages and in the shell holes of today. On the mount sits that tired, saddened, lonely figure, still compassionate, stil asking, "Forgive them for they know not what they do." (The above wording appears in the panel of the painting), 11-verso
    - Out Where the West Begins -Arthur Chapman [Poem], 12
    - "Out Where the West Begins" is a poem famous around the world as defining the spirit of West more effectively than anything written. It was written by Arthur Chapman, then a reporter on a Denver newspaper, on the occasion of a dispute as to the real boundary of the West. The poem and Mt. Holly Cross are two symbols of the marvelous West that are familiar to all., 12-verso
    - White Star Line. Twin-Screw T.M.S. "Homeric," 33,525 Tons., 13
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 13-verso
    - [Pan American airplane flying over mountains], 14
    - Pan American's Boeing 707-321B Super Intercontinental Jet Clipper* equipped with turbofan engines. Pan American flies to six continents with the worlds largest over-ocean Jet fleet. Pan American: World's Most Experienced Airline *trade-mark, Reg. U.S. Pat. Off., 14-verso
    - Al Farby: "We've entered him at Andover - And ordered two seats for 'Cinerama' for him"- Courtesy of Christian Science Monitor; [cartoon], 15